Hey how's it going to do to here
And this is the Acer Nitro
This is a laptop is geared towards that hoe Linux
Gaming Market
It's nine hundred bucks
It's got
A GTX 1050
TI 256
Pics of SSD
And a KB Lake
Japan
There's a lot of stuff that
I like about this thing but if you notice the title of this video
I don't openly recommend this thing to everybody and the reason why is because I feel like there's a better option than this
For people who are actually
And it's not because this is a bad laptop
This is actually a very good laptop
But I will see
There's something little bit better than
So the things that I do like it
First I really like the bills
This thing looks
Les gamer I should say then the average
Cheap gaming laptop
It has a red stripe down here but it's not that bright
Cherry red is Marla commuted
Metallic burgundy color
It's still red on my favorite thing but I think it's a lot better than a lot of gaming laptop
And everything else on the top at least is black even that logo the Acer logo is a
Simple black
And the components are chosen in here are good the 1050ti is that sweet spot for
Inexpensive 1080p
The port selection is pretty standard for this price you getting 3 used
CPAs in one USB
PC not done about 3
I like the screen it's amazing it's an IPS screen
And it looks
Not bad I mean it's
$900 gaming laptop you're not going to get
4K
Color accurate screens at this price
So yeah I'm happy with
The screen the keyboard and the trackpad are also both good
The keyboard is helpful to use nice layout
The one thing that's a little bit weird on the layer is it the shift
The up Arrow are really close together and I person didn't have any issues using it but I think it will depend on how your keyboard
Habits are
If you
Get your shift
In a particular way you might hit the other at the same time
But I'm having issues
Trackers also really good Windows Precision drivers Acer has totally gone into the whole Windows Precision driver thing
They don't use anymore alandur snapped
The drivers from what I've seen recently
So that's really nice
The speakers are located on the bottom and they don't sound terrible or anything they don't sound
Great but it's $900 gaming laptop
The kind of sound as you
The bills pulling in the Nitro 5 is good
Got a metal top panel but everything else is
Does plastic include in the bottom panel
But all the plastic parts
Feel good
Does access to the two and a half inch saddle Drive
And the ram slots
Patches but you want to go deeper you can remove the whole panel
The battery's down here it's a 48 watt hour battery and I'm getting a little bit less
Stand for hours about
Vanessa screen at 200
Depending what you do
I'll be around
And so far everything sounds good right everything
Seems
Proper on this laptop
But this is my one issue with this
The thermal design
Is
Not ideal
Here you can see the CPU and the GPU
To keep pipes that pull heat away from these chips
Which it cooled with
And I don't like seeing game laptops
Designed like this
So on a regular laptop that doesn't have
Ton of thermal output
This is fine
Because when it's very effective
And space efficient way of
Cooling things down
Put on a gaming laptop with a GTX 1050 TI
This is not ideal and what ends up happening
Is that the Heat
Receive you
How to travel along this pipe
Pasta GPU
Fornia cooled by the
Hi to fans and if you use your laptop for a really long time
The CPU build up heat
X15 is another inexpensive laptops
Nothing has a much better thermal design tool
They're still to keep pipes
And two fans
But because the two fans are located on opposite end
Each fan is going to pull
Keep more readily from the closer
Can you just get better thermal
Now if all you're doing
Is browsing the web or just doing light stuff
Are you done playing games for
Really short verse for like 15-20 minutes
Then you literally will never notice it you will not see any kind of thermal issues
But you play games for a long time
Over an hour
You'll notice that the CPU temperature starts
The creep up and up
And eventually you'll hit that way
The one thermal Advantage little to the Natural 5 has
If it does have cool boost
Technology which is basically built-in software
To allow you to
Control the fan
The vx15 does not have that
This does
And it can be helpful
The thing is you can always get
Like third-party software to control the fans but this has it straight from the factory
So the fan was on this thing
A title is not very loud it's actually
Quite quiet unload it's a little bit louder audible but not too bad
But with cool boost on this thing is quite loud
And it's still not good enough to maintain really high clock speeds
For extended periods of time despite it being
Super loud
So here's the thing
For $900
The market is
Very competitive rate
Now there's a lot of good options to choose from the vx15
The Delsym
I67 2
Upcoming 7577
This thing the Nitro
Survive there always
Kind of in that market
So if you're going to make a laptop
That competes
If you going to spend the time and the resources
Like a sir did
To make the nitrifying
Brand new laptop
Why like why not make it something just more different
That there's nothing about this thing that makes it a compelling purchase
Okay I take that back there's two things that are unique about
That don't matter to me but I'd to be fair I need to just kind of
Put this out there for full disclosure
This thing has a design like a visual design that's better than the other laptops
Competes with
The red isn't super obnoxious
And the rest of it is pretty simple
The screen is also ever so slightly better than the vx15 and the Dell sometimes
Nexus 7 screen they're all IPS but this one
Little brighter
Little bit more Color actor
Talking like
To 3%
So
If those are important to you and you don't want thermal issues
Sure go for this
But for most people I wouldn't recommend this
The Acer VX 15
Is just
Better already
Okay hope you guys enjoy this video thumbs we liked it sounds we loved it see you guys next time