Hey how's it going do you to be here
So this is Lenovo Legion y520 their mid-tier gaming laptop
And aesthetically I really like this
It feels nice to hold in your hand
And fingerprints don't show up too much
There's a full carbon fiber top and it's
Black everywhere even the logos
Most gaming laptops have some kind of red accents on the exterior
This doesn't
He pulled into lecture hall or even at work
No one would really notice
I also like the bronze or
Copper colored heatsink they can see through the back it's a pretty muted Bible to this laptop
Until you open it and you realize
There's red everywhere
Had to be fair about like the low-to-mid tear gaming laptops
This has not that much but it's there
The build quality is good it's on par with competitors in this price range
There isn't anything that feels poorly built
The chassis the screen
The hinges good to way better than the hinge on the older y50 or y700
The display is one of the better looking ones in the sub $1,000 gaming laptop
Teddy P color gamut is kind of mediocre in even after calibration color accuracy
The best but it's reasonably bright
And viewing angles are good cuz it's
IPS panel bezels aren't too thick
And the webcam look
The speakers are positioned nicely just below the screen
When you're playing games
It sounds like a projector
Right into your ears
The thing is these lack base there's
Decent volume but the lower frequencies just aren't there even when I'm playing around with you
Down at the keyboard we have a couple of different
Textures we haven't brushed finished up here
And then the rest of the deck
Is this kind of
Soft touch
The keyboard has red accents and red backlighting
The number pad on the right is a little different
Sephora
If your number pad Pro we just use number
Has often
You'll probably find
The rest of the Lord is good
Easy to type on
Keys have 120mm of travel
Keystrokes feel a little soft but comfortable to use I think most people will easily get you
The track put itself kind of feels like glass but I'm pretty sure it's plastic
It's just a nice smooth finish
Synaptics drivers but good tracking in Chester
Control the buttons are not.
Dedicated buttons
But they feel
Mediocre
Like the middle area X
Like a lever so the closer It Gets In The Middle
The harder it is to click you can only press it down on the sides and I just don't love this
The port selection is good
Does Ethernet use
YouTube and audio jack
And I never said we have HDMI
A pair of USB 3
An SD reader
SPC
There's no sign of a 3 support but that's just the norm at this time
To get inside you flip it over remove some
Screws and open it up we have a good amount of upgrade welcome
Does a two and a half inch Drive Bay
An empty slot that supports
Pcie the configurations with SSD drives have pretty good speeds
And he pop up this metal Shredder here you can access the ramp
The battery's down here it's relatively small we're looking at
45 watt hour battery
I'm getting a little less than 4 hours of regular used with the
The screen at 200
50 minutes
If you're playing games is going to close in 45 minutes
To an hour
I really wish they'd put a bigger battery in this thing but
That's a compromise you going to make it
Performance overall is good
It uses Katy Lake CPUs
And a GTX 1050 TI even on the base
This model I'm running the upgraded i7 configuration
But the game performs are going to be really similar but
This
And I-5
Does a more detailed video link in the description
But on the 1050ti
Can the 7700
HQ something lighter like OverWatch
70 frames per second on Ultra
On Highway looking at almost
On June 21st
Doom on Ultra will still float above six
Second
Basically any of them or off to my Shooters will play really nice
Beyond the system
Something a bit more demanding like
Battlefield 1 you need to drop the graphic
Hi to get into that 60 France
In general any of the current titles will play nicely on
Yeah it's the best value GPU for
If you're editing videos
This is still a great choice especially cuz
Two drives in there but if you didn't call or accurate work I would totally plug up a neck
External monitor
There is some thermal throttling if you posted by some benchmarks for
Long enough but I never know sudden any games
Even after hours of playing so should be good
Surface temperature even unload stays comfortable to use
There's also
Dream cooling mode and software to crank the fans up if you really want the best
Turbo performance the heat pipe layout isn't
My favorite is an older style design like the heat from the GPU has a
Pass through the sea
View along the pipe
The fans Austin spin on idle but
It's so quiet unload it can get a little louder. Too bad I didn't hit that fixstream fan mode I don't know when you actually use
Use this but if you do it gets very noisy
Okay so the Lenovo Legend y520
You're getting a device with
A lot of plastic materials but with good build quality
Decent IPS screen
Breitbart
Weak color game
Keyboard is good
Trackpad is good
Buns on the trackpad are not
So good
Inside
Dkb Lake CPU options
And the 1050
TTI deliver awesome performance
The dollar
Cooling is done reasonably well
The RAM and the storage are all easy to access for a few
Future upgrades
The battery is a little late we're looking around for hours of average
So this laptop
There's not much I just like about it it's
For this price point it's
Really good
The one advantage that I would say that Lenovo has
Over other competitors in this price point
Is that they often have
Pretty Goods
Tell the right now you can get us in for $850
That's what the 10:50
ATI that's
Really good my opinion
Trying to decide between this laptop and
The three or four other laptops that are in this price range
I will be doing a comparative review
I want to do it sooner than later but
There's a fourth
Laptop that came to mix
Two-player for entered the game I will be doing that video shortly and then I'll be doing
Comparative video
For all of them
Hope you guys enjoy this video sounds if you liked it
Subzi loved it