Do or do not.
There is no try.
All right,
I'll give it a try.
No!
Try not.
Do or do not.
There is no try.
It's nice because
it could be a load of things.
Because I don't think
doing the thing,
is the doing the thing.
It's just, if you try,
you're doing it anyway.
That's what I take from it.
I actually have three new
of my favorite Star Wars quotes.
-Oh, from this one?
-And they're all from this one.
They're incredible.
I'll go with,
"Never tell me the odds."
Oh, that's nice.
What are you doing?
You're not actually
going into an asteroid field?
They'd be crazy to follow us,
wouldn't they?
You don't have to do this
to impress me.
Sir, the possibility
of successfully navigating an asteroid field
is approximately
3,720 to 1.
Never tell me the odds.
I love everything that Yoda says
and I love Frank Oz's performance
in that movie.
When he says,
"Luminous beings are we--"
Its energy surrounds us,
and binds us.
Luminous beings are we,
not this crude matter.
Just the hint of kind of like
the bigger spiritual world of that
existing in this kind of pop,
you know, soap opera, space opera,
that, I don't know.
That's the first thing
that popped in my head.